BERNARD OWUSU ANSAH

Fullstack Engineer

Mobile: +233(0)561836525 | Website: https://ansah.pages.dev | Email: bernardansah5@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Resourceful software engineer with over 2 years of experience in developing frontend, backend systems and decentralized web applications. Founder of Mixxin, a decentralized application allowing easy transaction of cryptocurrencies. Extensive knowledge in smart contracts, consensus algorithms, and data structures. Looking for a job as a Fullstack Engineer that will allow me to build the financial system of tomorrow.

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant Oct 2020 – Sep 2021

Holy Child R/C Basic School, Sakumono

Holy Child R/C Basic School is one of the top basic schools in Sakumono, having won a number of STEM awards and producing some of the best results in the Basic Education Certification Examination in the community.

- Introduced students to JavaScript and Python programming languages, and increased the average literacy in Information Communication Technology (ICT) to 40%.
- Was part of a team who ushered an online learning platform for students during the covid-19 pandemic which reduced the infection rate from 30% to 0%.

Business Developer Jan 2020 – Feb 2020

TDK, Accra

TDK is a startup software solutions provider.

- Helped the sales team grow their territory sales by 20%.
- Assisted credit manager in account collection by phone and mail, increasing accounts receivables by 20%.

EDUCATION

Freecode camp 2019 - 2020

Software engineering

Accra Technical University

2017 - 2020

HND Marketing

SKILLS

Programming Languages - JavaScript, Solidity, Python, Typescript

Frontend – React, Next, Vue

Backend - Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, GraphQL, Firebase, Kubernetes

Development - Linux, Unit testing, Penetration testing, Git, Techical writing

Digital Marketing - Search Engine Marketing, Content marketing.

PROJECTS

Scinifie Oct 2022 - Nov 2022

Site: https://scinifie.pages.dev/ | Source code: https://github.com/1Bernard/scinifie

Scinifie is a modern disability friendly movie search app with voice recognition assistance using artificial intelligence, TMDB API, and React.

Liteplay Aug 2022 - Sep 2022

Site: https://liteplay.pages.dev/ | Source code: https://github.com/1Bernard/Liteplay

Liteplay is a music player web app that makes it easy to discover all the music you love to hear worldwide. The stack used are JavaScript, Tailwind css, Vite, Redux toolkit, Shazamcore Api, IP Geolocation API.

Mixxin Nov 2022 - Dec 2022

Site: https://mixxin.pages.dev/ | Source code: https://github.com/1Bernard/mixxin

Mixxin is a decentralized application for sending and receiving ethereum across the world. It incorporates metamask wallet authentication and solidity smart contracts.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Chatbot implementation – Developed a chatbot which helped customers to reduce costs by 200% in the customer service department.

Improved query efficiency – Increased query efficiency to 30% by designing and fully revising MySQL databases.

A member of Young Professionals And Youthful Coalition – A participant of the 10th transform summit, involved in sharing innovative ideas on entrepreneurship.

Published Poet – Was the only Ghanaian selected among a group of talented writers to showcase their art on an international magazine: New Reader Magazine, Volume 2 Issue 8.

INTERESTS

Blockchain technology, Entrepreneurship, Watching tech documentaries, Participating in social activities.